







Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Jump to Section Work

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Summary

Data scientist with over a year of experience in managing software and data science projects for MNC clients. Well versed with predictive modelling, data processing, and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems. Involved in Python open source community and passionate about brining machine learning, deep reinforcement learning to Business.

Work Experience

Rubixe as Data scientist intern May 2020 to Till Date

Fulfilled all data science duties for a high-end capital firm.

Have been working on Various ML and Al projects

- Cure fit as Centre Manager IT Mar 2020 to Jul 2020
- * Fulfilled all the day to day activities and analysis on various domains by collecting data.
- Frontdesk AI as Junior client support specialist Aug 2019 to Dec 2019

I have worked as Al trainer, we used to test various automated tool on real time basis and do analysis based on how we are handling. I was awarded the best performer by our CTO for completing 270 calls on an average everyday (quality analysis) per day successfully.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Ed (Education) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2019

PG: PG Diploma (Computers) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2019

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs

Important

Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Certified Data Scientist Certification on Power Bl and Workshop on Big data AWS Architect

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Python, Numpy, Pandas			
Sklearn, spark			
SQL, Cloud, AWS, Flask			
Data Visualization, Tableau			
Matplotlib, PowerBI			
Machine Learning Modeling			
Computer Vision		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Deep learning		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
MACHINE LEARNING		2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Kannada	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Telugu	Proficient	✓		✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: Forecasting Spare Parts Inventory

Client: Rubixe client

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2020 - Till Date
Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Started with initial domain analysis and data preprocessing.

Project Title: Cellphone Price Prediction

Client: Capstone

 Nature of Employment: Full Time
 Duration: Oct 2020 - Oct 2020

 Project Location: Bangalore
 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: there were few challenges in Data like miss naming of columns which was confusing we had to handle those, we tried to evaluate the model with couple of algorithm to check the accuracy, we finally came up with KNN giving the best accurancy

Project Title: Home Credit Default Risk ML project

Client: Capstone

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2020 - Oct 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Predicting customer who are eligible for Home loan based on credits. I am Involved from initial data preparation to model evaluation.

Project Title: Automobile Price Prediction ML Project

Client: Capstone

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2020 - Aug 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: I was involved from initial discussion of this project till the completion. I lead the initial data extraction and preparation phase with other colleagues. There was challenges with data, as there were significant wrong entries, missing values (about 20%). I performed EDA on the dataset in order to clean the data. Used Automobiles knowledge with data science technique to transform the data, used Linear Regression to create classifier with 95% accuracy.

Project Title: Heart Disease Prediction ML project

Client: Capstone

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2020 - Sep 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: I was involved from initial discussion of this project till the completion. I lead the initial data extraction and preparation phase with other colleagues. There was challenges with data, as there were

significant wrong entries, correlations between features. I performed EDA on the dataset in order to clean the data. Used Healthcare knowledge with data science technique to transform the data, used Couple of classification algorithm like logistic regression, SVM, KNN, Random forest and XGboost, Finally we came up to conclusion to use XGboost to create classifier with 96% accuracy

Project Title: ITSM Incident Management ML Project

Client: Rubixe Client

Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Bangalore

Project Details: I was involved from initial

discussion of this project till the final delivery. I lead the initial data extraction and preparation phase with other other colleagues. There was challenges with data, as there were significant wrong entries and human biases were present (about 30%). I used ITSM knowledge with data science technique to transform the data, used Random forest to create classifier with 92% accuracy. Project was successfully delivered

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

and deployed at client location.

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Duration: Jul 2020 - Aug 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.